A Collection of Scrapbooks LSC.0155
UCLA Library Special Collections
Scrapbook collection
1850-1950
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0155
88.5 Linear Feet (177 boxes)
Collection consists of scrapbooks, containing clippings, broadsides, manuscripts, portraits, photographs, and ephemera covering a variety of subjects, including the death of Edward VIII, Giuseppe Garibaldi, Southern California politics, Starege McCanless Swineford, Thomas Hardy, World War I, the Boer War, and the Spanish-American War.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942328673606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of scrapbooks, containing clippings, broadsides, manuscripts, portraits, photographs, and ephemera covering a variety of subjects, including the death of Edward VIII, Giuseppe Garibaldi, Southern California politics, Starege McCanless Swineford, Thomas Hardy, World War I, the Boer War, and the Spanish-American War.
Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbook no. 1: Overman Mining Company, San Francisco, 1867 - 1871; 112 p. (many blank); 22 cm (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings concerning the Overman Mining Company and the Sutro Tunnel taken chiefly from San Francisco newspapers
- Scrapbook no. 2: Jarboe and Harrison, Attorneys at law, San Francisco, 1865 - 1868; 229 p. (many blank); 23 cm (Box 1)
  Clippings from San Francisco newspapers concerning opinions delivered by various national and California State courts in regard to land titles in California. Alphabetical index in manuscript precedes clippings. Marked: Miscellaneous No. 2
- Scrapbook no. 3: The Ralston Memorial, San Francisco., 1875; 132 p.; 22 cm (in case) (Box 1)
  Scrapbook of clippings concerning the career and death of William C. Ralston (1826 - 1875). Prepared by A. Stein
- Scrapbook no. 4: Simpson, Mary Jane. Sundries [and] original matter, 1864 - 1876; 296 p. (last 89 blank); 25 cm (Box 1)
  Scrapbook compiled by Mary Jane Simpson, the San Francisco Chronicle's correspondent for Virginia City and the Washoe Mines. Contains her articles and additional material taken from S.F. and V.C. newspapers. Incl. W.C.Ralston letter (3/13/1871)
- Scrapbook no. 5: Bigelow, Henry H., Ca. 1866 - 1872; 142 p.; 27 cm (Box 1)
  Scrapbook containing clippings, broadsides and manuscripts relating to the insurance business in California and the United States, compiled by HHB, general manager of the San Francisco office of Home Mutual Ins. Co. and agent for Pacific Ins. Co.
- Scrapbook no. 6: Bornholm, bombardment of, May 8, 1945; 48 p.; 37 cm (Box 100)
  Scrapbook containing pictures and clippings taken from Stockholm newspapers. Gift of Jean Hersholt, May 11, 1949
- Scrapbook no. 7 vols. 1, 2: Hewitt, Leslie R., 1867 -, 1909 - 1910; 4 vols; 35 cm (Box 2)
  Newspaper and magazine clippings concerning the political activities of U.S. Senator Frank P. Flint, of Cal., and politics in Cal. Bound in odd vols. of the U.S. Senate and House Journals and the Congressional Record
- Scrapbook no. 7 vols. 3, 4: Hewitt, Leslie R., 1867 -, 1909 - 1910; 4 vols; 35 cm (Box 3)
  (See box 2 description)
- Scrapbook no. 8: California State Board of Harbor Commissioners, Engineer Department, documents, Ca. 1879 - 1884; 1 vol.; 38 cm (Box 9)
  Gummed stub file containing printed specifications issued by the Chief Engineer of the State Board of Harbor Commissioners for work to be done at San Francisco Harbor. Many specifications issued by Marsden Manson (1850 - 1931), Chief Engineer
- Scrapbook no. 9 vols. 2, 3: Moore, Walter S., 1895 - 1899; 3 vols; 31 - 35 cm (Box 4)
  Newspapers clippings and an accompanying documentary record of the history of the Los Angeles Fire Department. Included is a series of orders issued by Moore as Fire Chief of the Fire Department
- Scrapbook no. 9 vol. 1: Moore, Walter S., 1895 - 1899; 3 vols; 31 - 35 cm (Box 5)
  (See box 4 description)
- Scrapbook no. 10: Pease, Francis Gladheim (1881 - 1938), Ca. 1901 - 1938; 174 p.; 32 cm (Box 5)
  Photographs and newspapers clippings concerning astronomical instruments at Yerkes Observatory, Mount Wilson and Mount Palomar obervatories collected by Pease during his career as designer of astronomical instruments. Includes biographical material
- Scrapbook no. 11 vols. 1, 2: Kalloch - DeYoung, DeYoung - Kalloch shootings and trial, 1879 -1881; 2 vols; 23 cm (Box 5)
  Charles DeYoung (1845 - 1880) shot San Francisco mayorial candidate Isaac Smith Kalloch (1832 - 1890) on Aug. 23, 1879,and was himself killed by the mayor's son Isaac M. Kalloch (1853 - ) on Apr. 24, 1880. Robert E. Cowan collection
- Scrapbook no. 12: Wilmington, North Carolina. Clippings about local people and businesses, Ca. 1850 - 1870; 1 vol. (Box 1)
- Scrapbook no. 14 vols. 1, 2: Layne, Joseph Gregg (1885 - 1952), 1925; 4 vol (3 found 10/90); 31 - 40 cm (Box 6)
  Scrapbooks containing clippings taken chiefly from southern California newspapers and relating to subjects of historic interest in California. J. Gregg Layne Purchase, Aug., 1953
- Scrapbook no. 14 vol. 3: Layne, Joseph Gregg, 1885 - 1952, 1925; 4 vols (3 found 10/90); 31 - 40 cm (Box 7)
  (See box 6 description)
- Scrapbook no. 15 vols. 1, 2: Jackson, Grant, 1869 - 1925, 1923 - 1925; 37 cm (Box 8)
  Scrapbooks containing clippings taken chiefly from southern California newspapers relating to subjects of historic interest in California. GJ was a judge of the Los Angeles Superior Court. Partial copy in neg. mic. coll. Layne Purchase, Aug., 1953
- Scrapbook no. 16: Los Angeles City Aqueduct in pictures with notes, Ca. 1920; 54 p.; 29 cm (Box 7)
  Loose leaf binder. J. Gregg Layne Purchase, Aug., 1953
- Scrapbook no. 17: Scrapbook concerning southern California politics, 1878 - 1884; 32 cm (Box 7)
  Ephemera and clippings taken chiefly from Los Angeles newspapers and reflecting mainly opinion of the southern section of California concerning the Constitutionsal Convention of 1879, The Workingmen's Party, the Temperance Movement and local politics
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 1: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 119)
  Vols. 1-9 are titled: "A history of World War II from the invasion of Poland to the entry of the United States, collected from the daily prints." Clippings chiefly from the Chritian Science Monitor
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 2: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 120)
  (see vol. 1 description)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 3: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 94)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 4: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 92)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 5: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 121)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 6: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 122)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 7: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 123)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 8: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 93)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 9: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, Ca. 1939 - 1941; 13 vols. (Box 124)
- Scrapbook no. 18 vols. 11, 12: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, 1941 - 1945; 13 volumes (Box 125)
  see vol. 10 description
- Scrapbook no. 18 vol. 13: McClurkin, James Robert, 1910 -. Scrapbooks re: World War II, 1941 - 1945; 13 volumes (Box 126)
- Scrapbook no. 19: Wilson, James, 1862 - 1884; 101 p.; 24 cm (Box Unknown container 1493 for instance of Scrapbook no. 19: Wilson, James)
  Scrapbook containing clippings chiefly from Wilmington, North Carolina newspapers relating to Wilson's career as an alderman, mayor, real estate broker and owner of a harness establishment in Wilmington, NC. Aldine purchase. Not found, 10/90
- Scrapbook no. 20: Scrapbook of clippings relating to the Boer War, 1899 - 1900; 1 vol.; 31 cm (Box 9)
  Scrapbook of clippings relating to the Boer War taken chiefly from London newspapers. A few manuscript items are included. British Empire Collection Fund
- Scrapbook no. 21: Scrapbook of clippings relating to the Spanish - American War, 1898; 1 vol.; 30 cm (Box Unknown container 1494 for instance of Scrapbook no. 21: Scrapbook of clippings relating to the Spanish - American War)
  Scrapbook of clippings relating to the Spanish - American War, including a few later clippings concerning U.S. Army and Philippine independence. Clippings are mostly undated and taken chiefly from Washington, D.C. newpapers. Gift of Clark J. Milliron
- Scrapbook no. 23 vol. 1: Collins, James H., vol.1: 11/30/99 - 12/07; 31 - 40 cm (Box 110)
  Scrapbooks documenting the development of business, advertising, and technology in the USA. Consists chiefly of articles and pamphlets by JHC, one of the foremost writers on business and advertising in the early 20th century. Gift of JHC, 22/9/1954
- Scrapbook no. 23 vol. 2: Collins, James H., vol.2: 7/05 - 4/17; 31 - 40 cm (Box 111)
- Scrapbook no. 23 vol. 3: Collins, James H., vol. 3:2/07 - 26/11/10; 34 - 40 cm (Box 113)
- Scrapbook no. 23 vol. 4: Collins, James H., vol. 4: 25/3/11 - 2/2/15; 31 - 40 cm (Box 112)
- Scrapbook no. 23 vol. 5: Collins, James H., vol. 5: 20/12/13 - 20/9/17; 31 - 40 cm (Box 108)
- Scrapbook no. 23 vol. 6: Collins, James H., vol. 6: 22/7/17 - 13/5/19; 31 - 40 cm (Box 109)
- Scrapbook no. 25: California State Supreme Court, 1864; 1 vol.; 38 cm (Box 18)
  Printed decisions of the California State Supreme Court for the April and July terms, 1864. The decisions, as printed in the Sacramento Daily Union, are pasted in the volume alphabetically by plaintiff. With index to cases and decisions.
- Scrapbook no. 26: Combined Comstock Co., San Francisco, 1875 - 1877; 1 vol.; 31 cm (Box 13)
  Clippings and brocures concerning the Combined Comstock Co., but including some on the Comstock Lode and Comstock mining stocks. The clippings are from San Francisco newspapers
- Scrapbook no. 27: Local and county notes, Sept. 1891. San Francisco and Oakland, 1 vol. (Box 13)
- Scrapbook no. 28: The past century; its progress in great subjects. Sun Printing and Publishing Association, New York, 1900 - 1901; 85 p.; 27 cm (Box 19)
  A series of articles appearing in the New York Daily Sun on the progress of science, religion, government and society during the nineteenth century. Gift of Mrs. J. Morris Slemons, Feb., 1955
- Scrapbook no. 29: Smith, Wallace, 1895 -. Spanish exploration in the San Joaquin, 1925 - 1926, 1923 - 1927; 86 p.; 22 cm (Box 19)
  A series of fifteen articles on Spanish exploration of the San Joaquin Valley, by Wallace Smith, Vice Principal of Kingsburg high school, published in the Fresno Republican. Included are clippings from the Republican re the history of the S.J.Valley
- Scrapbook no. 30: Remsburg, George. California Indian, 1926 - 1928; 90 p.; 21 cm (Box 19)
  Clippings relating to the Indians of California, chiefly from the Los Angeles Times and Fresno Republican, compiled by George Remsburg, Kansas journalist. Purchased from Lipsey, Nov. 15, 1954
- Scrapbook no. 31: [Civil War scrapbook], Nov. 5, 1860 - Mar. 4, 1861; 214 p. (Box 19)
  Clippings and illustrations, chiefly from the New York Tribune and Harper's Weekly, covering the period from the election of Abraham Lincoln to his inauguration. Includes ms subject index. Gift of Ralph Blasingame, 1954
- Scrapbook no. 32: Carlyle, Christine and Hazel Breckenridge, Pima medical and utility plants, Ca. 1940; 1 vol. (Box 105)
  Essays on Pima medical and utility plants with mounted examples, by Christine Carlyle and Hazel Breckinridge, under the direction of Elnora White,an, Gila Crossing Day School, Kamatke, Arizona. Holograph ms
- Scrapbook no. 33: Reams, Zelma, and Lenora Smith, Ca. 1940; 1 vol. (Box 68)
  Early Pima foods, by Zelma Reams and Lenora Smith, under the direction of Elnora Whiteman, Gila Crossing Day School, Komathe, Arizona. Holograph ms.
- Scrapbook no. 35 vols. 1, 2: Point Park Commission, Pittsburg, Penn., Dec. 31, 1943; 2 vols (Box 18)
  Material copied from the Report of the Point Park Commission, Pittsburg, Penn., concerning the restoration of Fort Pitt on the present site of Pittsburg, Penn., with a view to its inclusion as a National Historical Site. Carbon typescript
- Scrapbook no. 37: Greenaway, Kate, N.D.; 13 items (Box 13)
  Scrapbook of greeting cards by Kate Greenaway and others. Purchase: Mrs. E.R, Mocine, Jan. 25, 1954
- Scrapbook no. 38, misc.: United National Clothing Collection Committee / Victory Clothing Collection for Overseas Relief, Ca. 1945; 5 vols. (Box 76)
  A collection of promotional material issued at the close of World War II for the purpose of collecting clothing for peoples throughout the world
- Scrapbook no. 38, vol. 1: United National Clothing Collection Committee / Victory Clothing Collection for Overseas Relief, Ca. 1945; 5 vols. (Box 104)
- Scrapbook no. 38, vol. 2: United National Clothing Collection Committee / Victory Clothing Collection for Overseas Relief, Ca. 1945; 5 vols. (Box 103)
- Scrapbook no. 38, vol. 3: United National Clothing Collection Committee / Victory Clothing Collection for Overseas Relief, Ca. 1945; 5 vols. (Box 99)
- Scrapbook no. 38, vol. 4: United National Clothing Collection Committee / Victory Clothing Collection for Overseas Relief, Ca. 1945; 5 vols. (Box 100)
- Scrapbook no. 38, records: United National Clothing Collection Committee / Victory Clothing Collection for Overseas Relief, Ca. 1945; 5 vols. (Box 107)
  A collection of promotional material issued at the close of World War II for the purpose of collecting clothing for peoples throughout the world.
- Scrapbook no. 39, vol. 1: World War I, June 11 - July 7, 1917; 2 vols (Box 10)
  Clippings taken chiefly from the Seattle Times concerning World War I. Gift of Mrs. Goldie Moss
- Scrapbook no. 39, vol. 2: World War I, Sept. 13 - Nov. 12, 1917; 2 vols. (Box 11)
  Clippings taken chiefly from the Seattle Times concerning World War I. Gift of Crs. Goldie Moss
- Scrapbook no. 40: Victorian scrapbook of miscellaneous poems, letters, portraits, sketches and water colors, Ca. 1830 - 1860; 1 vol. (Box 18)
  Water colors are of various English and European scenes, birds, butterflies, and flowers. At front: Ashbury, Novbr.
- Scrapbook no. 41: Dodge, John Mason (1853 - 1951), Ca. 1860 - 1950; 1 vol. (Box 115)
  Newspaper articles relating to the life of Jack Dodge in San Diego, Cal.
- Scrapbook no. 42: Randall, Jerome, Ca. 1907; 1 vol. (Box 18)
  Newspaper clippings and magazine articles relating to current events in the U.S.
- Scrapbook no. 43: Giuseppe Garibladi scrapbook, Ca. 1878 - 1910; 8 unnumbered, 1 mounted; 40 cm (Box 20)
  Scrapbook concerning Giuseppe Garibaldi. Contains a holograph note of Garibaldi's dated Jan 25, 1878; clippings, pictures and some facsimile documents
- Scrapbook no. 44 vols. 1, 2: Flint, Frank Putnam, 1862 - 1929, 2/6/1909 - 1/31/1911; 7 vols.; 30 cm (Box 40)
- Scrapbook no. 44, vols. 3, 6: Flint, Frank Putnam, 1862 - 1929, 2/6/1909 - 1/31/1911; 7 vols.; 30 cm (Box 41)
- Scrapbook no. 44, vol. 4: Flint, Frank Putnam, 1862 - 1929, 2/6/1909 - 1/31/1911; 7 vols.; 30 cm (Box 58)
- Scrapbook no. 44, vols. 5, 7: Flint, Frank Putnam, 1862 - 1929, 2/6/1909 - 1/31/1911; 7 vols.; 30 cm (Box 42)
- Scrapbook no. 45: Giffen, Guy J., Ca. 1929 - 1945; 3 vols.; 28 - 30 cm (Box 63)
  Correspondence of Giffen's concerning Western outlaws and pioneers together with photographs and clippings. Gift of Paul I. Wellman, 7/6/60
- Scrapbook no. 46: Brady, Cyrus Townsend, 1861 - 1920, Ca. 1912; 1 vol. (Box 20)
  The island of the stairs, by Cyrus Townsend Brady, bound with Burgess, Thornton W. Bedtime stories. Contains newspaper clippings which are pasted over the pages of the Report of the thirteenth international Christian Endeavor convention, 1894
- Scrapbook no. 47: [Concerning Thomas Hardy], Ca. 1861 - 1829; 1 vol. (Box 20)
  A collection of 60 portraits of Thomas Hardy, at various ages. Also included are views of places mentioned in his novels, etc.
- Scrapbook no. 48: Lighthouses of the California coast, 37 p.; 28 cm (Box 20)
  Typescript with mounted clippings and photographs in ring binder
- Scrapbook no. 49, vol. 1: 19th century costumes and calling cards, 1826 - 1845; 2 vols. (Box 101)
  A collection of 19th century costumes and calling cards. On the cover: The Countess of Coventry. Gift of William Andrews Clark Library
- Scrapbook no. 49, vol. 1: 19th century costumes and calling cards, 1826 - 1845; 2 vols. (Box 117)
  A collection of 19th century costumes and calling cards. On cover: The Countess of Coventry. Gift of William Andrews Clark Library
- Scrapbook no. 50, vols. 1, 2: Peiper, Lulu E., Ca. 1882 - 1910; 4 vols. (Box 20)
  Scrapbooks compiled by Miss Lulu E. Peiper containing notices and programs for her appearances as a soprano soloist in Los Angeles and other places, but also including photographs of her family and friends together
- Scrapbook no. 50, vols. 3, 4: Peiper, Lulu E., Ca. 1882 - 1910; 4 vols. (Box 21)
- Scrapbook no. 51: Daughters of the American Colonists, Los Angeles Chapter, 1925 - 1954 (Box Unknown container 1495 for instance of Scrapbook no. 51: Daughters of the American Colonists, Los Angeles Chapter)
  Scrapbook recording activities of the LA Chapter of the DAC compiled by various chapter officers. Includes clippings, photographs, printed programs, etc. with some material re nat'l & state DAC activities, gift of Mrs. H.Maxwell. NOT FOUND 11/90
- Scrapbook no. 52: Hendrichs, Herrmann, 1809 - (Box 20)
  Scrapbook containing clippings and photographs about the theatrical career of German actor Herrmann Hendrichs. From the Georg Altman collection
- Scrapbook no. 53: Dace, Catherine Porter (Hubbard), 1886 - 1961, 1915 - 1959; 1 vol.; 59 cm (Box 106)
  Letters, manuscripts, clippings, photographs and related printed material concerning Mrs. Dace's activities in the national society of the Daughters of the American Colonists, her family, and San Fernando Valley history. Gift of Henry H. Dace, 6/62
- Scrapbook no. 54: Theater scrapbook, Chicago, 1926 - 1939; 1 v.; 30 cm (Box 118)
  Programs and photographs of plays performed in Chicago
- Scrapbook no. 55: Trade cards, 1870 - 1900; 1 v.; 37 1/2 cm (Box 118)
  Trade cards issued in San Jose, Cal. In light green cloth box
- Scrapbook no. 56: Actors and actresses in stage costume, Ca. 1870 - 1900; 2 v.; 37 cm (Box 74)
  Portraits and identified
- Scrapbook no. 58: An editorial history of the administration of President John F. Kennedy, 1960 - 1964; 246 p.; 29 cm (Box 22)
  Scrapbook of editorials from four major California newspapers, arranged chronologically. Compiled under the Oral history project, University of California, Los Angeles
- Scrapbook no. 59 vol.1: Lane, Harold M. Scrapbook of clippings of book reviews and articles about Japan, 1951 - 1963; 3 vols. (Box 15)
  Primarily English language materials. Incl. Mock Joya's column in the Japan Times. Book review are indexed. Gift of Earl Miner
- Scrapbook no. 59 vol.2: Lane, Harold M. Scrapbook of clippings of book reviews and articles about Japan, 1951 - 1963; 3 vols. (Box 16)
- Scrapbook no. 59 vol.3: Lane, Harold M. Scrapbook of clippings of book reviews and articles about Japan, 1951 - 1963; 3 vols. (Box 17)
- Scrapbook no. 60: Various clippings, 1895 - 1910; 1 v.; 29 cm (Box 14)
  Clippings of poetry, obituaries and articles concerning California and the West. Gift of Margaret Cressaty.
- Scrapbook no. 61: Theater programs, 1894 - 1924; 1 v.; 30 cm (Box 14)
  Primarily Chicago theater programs, but also New York and British
- Scrapbook no. 62: Raye, William Russell, 1840 - 1960; 1 v.; 28 cm (Box 55)
  Scrapbook of William Russell Raye and Rosa Raye. Contains poetry clippings and some letters
- Scrapbook no. 63: Civil War scrapbook and diary, Ca. 1860 - 1865; 1 v.; 33 cm (Box 22)
  Various unidentified clippings, and apparently a recipt book and diary kept by one or more persons
- Scrapbook no. 64: Dust wrapper album, Ca. 1900 - 1940; 1 v.; 27 cm (Box 58)
  Primarily early 20th century British dust wrappers
- Scrapbook no. 65: Book binding reproductions album, 1 v.; 27 cm (Box 43)
  From the Hoepli collection
- Scrapbook no. 66: Cigarette cards album, 1 v.; 30 cm (Box 55)
  Album of cigarette cards collected by Samuel E. Wurgin, Jr. of San Francisco. Includes black and white and colored cigarette cards
- Scrapbook no. 67: Pan-American Exposition, 1901, Buffalo, New York, 1 v.; 45 cm (Box 70)
  Printed matter, blanks, forms & circular letters of the Department of Commerce, Horticulture, Forestry & Foods & their accessories of the Pan-American Exposition. Also some from the S. Carolina & W. Indian Expo. (1902) & World's Columbian Expo. (1893)
- Scrapbook no. 68: Hollywood for Dewey, 1944; 1 v.; 40 cm (Box 91)
  Photographs, clippings, publicity and correspondence of the Hollywood comittee to support the 1944 Thomas E. Dewey presidential campaign
- Scrapbook no. 69: Dorsey, James M., scrapbook, Ca. 1835 - 1850; 1 v.; 46 cm (Box 71)
  Newspaper clippings from various papers, pasted in an account book dated Greenville [Ohio?] 1838
- Scrapbook no. 70: Ruth, Edward S., MD, 1 v.; 38 cm (Box 116)
  Dr. Ruth was for many years the physician for UCLA's athletic teams
- Scrapbook no. 71: Play reviews scrapbook, Ca. 1940 - 1945; 1 v. (Box Unknown container 1496 for instance of Scrapbook no. 71: Play reviews scrapbook)
  Newspaper reviews of theater productions in the United States and abroad. Not found 11/90
- Scrapbook no. 72: Letter book, Ca. 1900; 1000 l. (Box 13)
  This fine example of an unused letter book was made by Bailey Manufacturing Co., Hartford, Conn.
- Scrapbook no. 73: Chicago Opera scrapbook, 1929; 1 v. (Box 73)
  Press and magazine clippings relating to the Chicago Opera season of 1929
- Scrapbook no. 74 vol.1: MacDonald, Jeanette, 1907 - 1965. "Empire. Paris, 1931" (Box 59)
  Mounted newspapers clippings, press reviews, photographs and programs documenting Jeanette MacDonald's movie, stage and opera career. Gift of Jeanette MacDonald
- Scrapbook no. 74 vol.2-3: MacDonald, Jeanette, 1907 - 1965. Scrapbook, ca.1942-3, and "Concert 1946. British Isles.", 1942 - 1946 (Box 60)
- Scrapbook no. 74 vol. 4-5: MacDonald, Jeanette, 1907 - 1965. Scrapbook, ca. 1943-51, and "Guardsman" 1951, 1943 - 1951 (Box 61)
- Scrapbook no. 75 vols. 1-4: Scrapbooks on various subjects, 10 volumes with index, Ca. 1900 - 1935 (Box 23)
  Articles from journals and magazines, bound together and indexed by volume. Incl. materials on volcanoes, map-making, polar regions, radio development, and Germany from 1919 - 1932
- Scrapbook no. 75 vols. 5-8: Scrapbooks on various subjects, 10 volumes with index, Ca. 1900 - 1935 (Box 24)
- Scrapbook no. 75 vols. 9-10: Scrapbooks on various subjects, 10 volumes with index, Ca. 1900 - 1935 (Box 25)
- Scrapbook no. 76: Portraits of 17th and 18th century Europeans, Ca. 1800; 1 v.; 54 cm (Box 76)
  Approximately 670 engravings and mezzotints, primarily removed from books
- Scrapbook no. 77: Dickson, Edward Augustus, 1879 - 1956, collector. Literary fragments, Ca. 1930; 1 v.; 52 cm (Box Unknown container 1497 for instance of Scrapbook no. 77: Dickson, Edward Augustus, 1879 - 1956, collector. Literary fragments)
  Early examples of mauscripts and printing. Not found 11/90
- Scrapbook no. 78: Sovereigns of England, Ca. 1910; 1 v.; 50 cm (Box 77)
  Portraits from King William the Conquerer to King George V
- Scrapbook no. 79: Beginning of the Hanoverians, Ca. 1840; 1 v.; 35 cm (Box 78)
  Portraits of prominent Europeans